Guide to the Hisham Khatib Collection of photographic prints AD.MC.030
Akkasah: Photography Archive (NYU Abu Dhabi)
- Palestine, Damascus and Lebanon - Bonfils, Circa 1867-1880; ref725 (Object Digital Copy Only - 030_ref376-317)
  - 287- Porte de Damas - The Damascus gate., Circa 1867-1880; ref393; Bonfils, Felix; 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital Copy Only - 030_ref376-317)
    Photographic Prints; Albumen Prints; Damascus Gate, Jerusalem; Palestine; Architecture; Buildings; Forts/Castles; French Writing; English Writing; Archaeological Sites/Artifacts; Streets/Roads; Group Portraits; Men; Women; Regional/National Dress; Head Covers/Veils
  - 288 - Tombeau de David sur le Mont Sion - Tomb of David on Mount Zion., Circa 1867-1880; ref394; Bonfils, Felix; 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital Copy Only - 030_ref376-317)
    Photographic Prints; Albumen Prints; French Writing; English Writing; Tombs/Mausoleums; Jerusalem; Palestine; Religious Sites; Buildings; Architecture
  - 278 - Vue générale de la mosquée d'Omar - General view of the mosque of Omar (Dome of the Rock, Jerusalem)., Circa 1867-1880; ref395; Bonfils, Felix; 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital Copy Only - 030_ref376-317)
    Photographic Prints; Albumen Prints; Jerusalem; Palestine; Buildings; Architecture; Dome of the Rock/Qubbat al-Sakhrah; Religious Sites; Men; French Writing; English Writing; Temple Mount/al-Ḥaram al-Šarīf; Mosques; Archaeological Sites/Artifacts; Tombs/Mausoleums
  - 279 - Intérieur de la mosquée Omar, le Rocher - Interior of the Mosque of Omar: The Rock (Dome of the Rock, Jerusalem)., Circa 1867-1880; ref396; Bonfils, Felix; 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital Copy Only - 030_ref376-317)
    Photographic Prints; Albumen Prints; French Writing; English Writing; Architecture; Buildings; Dome of the Rock/Qubbat al-Sakhrah; Jerusalem; Palestine; Archaeological Sites/Artifacts
  - 304 - Jardin de Gethsemané - The Garden of Gethsemane., Circa 1867-1880; ref397; Bonfils, Felix; 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital Copy Only - 030_ref376-317)
    Photographic Prints; Albumen Prints; French Writing; English Writing; Jerusalem; Palestine; Men; Regional/National Dress; Architecture; Buildings; Forts/Castles; Gethsemane, Jerusalem; Religious Sites; Landscapes; Mountains/Hills; Gardens; Individual Portraits; Archaeological Sites/Artifacts
  - 274 - Coupoles du St Sépulcre (Cupolas of the church of the Holy Sepulchre, Jerusalem)., Circa 1867-1880; ref398; Bonfils, Felix; 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital Copy Only - 030_ref376-317)
    Photographic Prints; Albumen Prints; Buildings; Church of the Holy Sepulchre; Jerusalem; Palestine; French Writing; Architecture; Religious Sites; Churches; Religious Crosses
  - 278 - Mosque Of Omar (A view of the Dome of the Rock)., Circa 1867-1880; ref399; Bonfils, Felix; 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital Copy Only - 030_ref376-317)
    Photographic Prints; Albumen Prints; Buildings; Architecture; Religious Sites; Dome of the Rock/Qubbat al-Sakhrah; Archaeological Sites/Artifacts; Jerusalem; Palestine; Al-Aqsa Mosque/al-Masjid al-ʾAqṣā
  - Original description of the collection., Circa 1867-1880; ref517; 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital Copy Only - 030_ref376-317)
- Palestine by Bonfils, F.M. Good et al, ref726 (Object Digital copy only: 030_ref400-ref421)
  - Holy sites in Jerusalem., Circa 1867-1900; ref400; Unknown; 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital copy only: 030_ref400-ref421)
    Albumen Prints; Photographic Prints; Religious Sites; Palestine; Dome of the Rock/Qubbat al-Sakhrah; Gethsemane, Jerusalem; Landscapes; Mountains/Hills; Mount of Olives/Jabal al-Zaytun, Jerusalem; Churches; Church of the Holy Sepulchre; Mount Zion/Jabal Sahyoun, Jerusalem; Buildings; Architecture; English Writing; French Writing; Church of the Sepulchre of Saint Mary/Tomb of Saint Mary; Temple Mount/al-Ḥaram al-Šarīf
  - 275 - Porte dorée extérieur, Jérusalem (The Golden Gate, Jerusalem)., Circa 1867-1880; ref401; Bonfils, Felix; 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital copy only: 030_ref400-ref421)
    Albumen Prints; Photographic Prints; Jerusalem; Palestine; Buildings; Architecture; Golden Gate, Jerusalem; Temple Mount/al-Ḥaram al-Šarīf; Religious Sites; Archaeological Sites/Artifacts; French Writing
  - 893 - Grotte de la Nativité: la crêche - Cave of the Nativity: the manger (Bethlehem)., Circa 1867-1880; ref402; Bonfils, Felix; 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital copy only: 030_ref400-ref421)
    Albumen Prints; Photographic Prints; Bethlehem; Palestine; Church of the Nativity; Caves; Churches; Tapestry; Religious Sites; Religious Imagery; English Writing; French Writing; West Bank
  - 323 - Pool of Siloe (Pool of Siloam, Silwan)., Circa 1867-1880; ref403; Bonfils, Felix; 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital copy only: 030_ref400-ref421)
    Albumen Prints; Photographic Prints; Siloam/Silwan; Lakes; Landscapes; Mountains/Hills; Religious Sites; Palestine
  - 344 - Montagne de la Quarantaine - Mount of Temptation., Circa 1867-1880; ref404; Bonfils, Felix; 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital copy only: 030_ref400-ref421)
    Photographic Prints; Albumen Prints; Mount Quarantania/Jabal al-Qarantal, Jericho; West Bank; Landscapes; Mountains/Hills; French Writing; English Writing; Jericho; Palestine
  - 851 - Intérieur du St Sépulcre aux ornements (A view of the interior of the Church of the Holy Sepulchre, Jerusalem)., Circa 1867-1900; ref405; Unknown; 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital copy only: 030_ref400-ref421)
    Albumen Prints; Photographic Prints; French Writing; English Writing; Men; Group Portraits; Religious Sites; Churches; Church of the Holy Sepulchre; Buildings; Architecture; Religious Imagery; Statues/Sculptures; Chandeliers; Facial Hair; Priests/Clergymen; Hats; Jerusalem; Palestine
  - A group of people with camels and donkeys., Circa 1867-1880; ref406; Bonfils, Felix; 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital copy only: 030_ref400-ref421)
    Albumen Prints; Photographic Prints; Men; Camels; Animals; Mountains/Hills; Landscapes; Women; Children; Donkeys
  - 863 Jérusalem. Détails intérieurs de la mosquée El-Aksa (A view of the interior of the Al-Aqsa mosque, Jerusalem)., Circa 1867-1880; ref407; Bonfils, Felix; 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital copy only: 030_ref400-ref421)
    Albumen Prints; Photographic Prints; French Writing; Al-Aqsa Mosque/al-Masjid al-ʾAqṣā; Jerusalem; Buildings; Architecture; Religious Sites; Chandeliers; Mosques; Palestine; Temple Mount/al-Ḥaram al-Šarīf; Arabic Calligraphy
  - 297 - Eglise du Pater, intérieur - Church of the Pater Noster., Circa 1867-1880; ref408; Bonfils, Felix; 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital copy only: 030_ref400-ref421)
    Photographic Prints; Albumen Prints; Palestine; Buildings; Architecture; Religious Sites; Churches; English Writing; French Writing; Mount of Olives/Jabal al-Zaytun, Jerusalem; Church of the Pater Noster
  - 417 - Damas. Mur par où Saint Paul s'est enfui (Bab Kisan)., Circa 1867-1880; ref409; Bonfils, Felix; 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital copy only: 030_ref400-ref421)
    Photographic Prints; Albumen Prints; Damascus, Syria; Forts/Castles; Religious Sites; Buildings; Architecture; French Writing; English Writing; Streets/Roads
  - 915 - Halte des voyageurs sur les bords du Jourdain (Resting place of the travellers on the shores of the Jordan river)., Circa 1867-1880; ref410; Bonfils, Felix; 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital copy only: 030_ref400-ref421)
    Photographic Prints; Albumen Prints; French Writing; Jordan River; Individual Portraits; Rivers; Men; Regional/National Dress; Group Portraits; Bedouins; Facial Hair; Water
  - 837 - Plateau de Mizpa - Platform of Mizpa (a watchtower)., Circa 1867-1880; ref411; Bonfils, Felix; 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital copy only: 030_ref400-ref421)
    Photographic Prints; Albumen Prints; Buildings; Palestine; French Writing; English Writing; Landscapes
  - 286 - Souk-El-Trouk, Tunis., Circa 1870-1900; ref412; Etablissements Photographiques de Neurdein Freres (ND Phot), Paris (France); 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital copy only: 030_ref400-ref421)
    Albumen Prints; Photographic Prints; Tunis, Tunisia; Street Lamps; Street Vendors; Men; French Writing; Markets; Shops; Signs/Signposts; Architecture; Streets/Roads; Men; Regional/National Dress; Turbans; Hats; Individual Portraits
  - Four photographs of people and animals., Circa 1870-1910; ref413; Unknown; 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital copy only: 030_ref400-ref421)
    Albumen Prints; Photographic Prints; Men; Women; Children; Animals; Camels; Regional/National Dress; Buildings; Streets/Roads
  - 334 - Eglise de la Nativité, intérieur - Church of the Nativity, interior., Circa 1867-1880; ref414; Bonfils, Felix; 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital copy only: 030_ref400-ref421)
    Photographic Prints; Albumen Prints; Church of the Nativity; Churches; Religious Sites; Architecture; Buildings; Bethlehem; West Bank; Palestine; Religious Imagery; Religious Crosses; French Writing; English Writing
  - Fishermen at the shore of the Sea of Galillee., Circa 1867-1900; ref415; Unknown; 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital copy only: 030_ref400-ref421)
    Albumen Prints; Photographic Prints; Men; Children; Hats; Regional/National Dress; Boats/Ships; Landscapes; Mountains/Hills; Lakes; Sea of Galilee/Lake Tiberias; Palestine; Transportation; English Writing; Fishing; Galilee
  - Mont Thabor (Mount Tabor)., Circa 1867-1900; ref416; Scutschi, Lutuf; 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital copy only: 030_ref400-ref421)
    Albumen Prints; Photographic Prints; Landscapes; Mountains/Hills; Individual Portraits; Outdoors; Men; Animals; Horses; Mount Tabor/Jabal at-Tur; English Writing; Palestine
  - 236 - Jaffa, vue de la mer (Port of Jaffa)., Circa 1867-1880; ref417; Bonfils, Felix; 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital copy only: 030_ref400-ref421)
    Albumen Prints; Photographic Prints; Buildings; Seas; Jaffa; Palestine; Boats/Ships; Transportation; Docks/Piers/Jetties; Landscapes
  - Monastery of Mar Saba., Circa 1867-1880; ref418; Unknown; 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital copy only: 030_ref400-ref421)
    Albumen Prints; Photographic Prints; Buildings; Architecture; Monasteries/Convents; Mar Saba/The Holy Lavra of Saint Sabbas the Sanctified; Religious Sites; Bethlehem; West Bank; Palestine; Mountains/Hills; Archaeological Sites/Artifacts; Landscapes
  - Colonnade of Herod at Samaria (Sebastia)., Circa 1867-1880; ref419; Unknown; 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital copy only: 030_ref400-ref421)
    Albumen Prints; Photographic Prints; Individual Portraits; Men; Outdoors; Samaria/as-Sāmirah; Palestine; Architecture; Archaeological Sites/Artifacts; English Writing; Regional/National Dress; Facial Hair; Turbans
  - A portrait of a man facing left, wearing a cape and a turban., Circa 1867-1900; ref420; Unknown; 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital copy only: 030_ref400-ref421)
    Albumen Prints; Photographic Prints; Turbans; Individual Portraits; Regional/National Dress; Men; Facial Hair
  - A city surrounded by empty land., Circa 1867-1900; ref421; Unknown; 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital copy only: 030_ref400-ref421)
    Albumen Prints; Landscapes; Buildings; Deserts; Mountains/Hills; Photographic Prints
- Palestine Exploration Fund 1866-67, ref727 (Object Digital Copy Only - 030_ref422-ref425)
  - A view of Nimrod Fortress (Qal'at al-Subeiba)., Circa 1865-1866; ref422; Phillips, Henry, Sergeant, Active 1865-1867; 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital Copy Only - 030_ref422-ref425)
    Photographic Prints; Albumen Prints; Forts/Castles; English Writing; Landscapes; Buildings; Banias, Golan Heights; Nimrod Fortress; Archaeological Sites/Artifacts; Palestine; Mountains/Hills
  - Original PEF catalogue description of ref422, no date; ref423; 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital Copy Only - 030_ref422-ref425)
    Printed Materials
  - A view of Chorazin archaeological site in Northern Palestine., 1866; ref424; Phillips, Henry, Sergeant, Active 1865-1867; 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital Copy Only - 030_ref422-ref425)
    Albumen Prints; Photographic Prints; Archaeological Sites/Artifacts; English Writing; Buildings; Landscapes; Palestine; Galilee
  - A view of Chorazin archaeological site in Northern Palestine., 1866; ref425; Phillips, Henry, Sergeant, Active 1865-1867; 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital Copy Only - 030_ref422-ref425)
    Albumen Prints; Photographic Prints; Palestine; Archaeological Sites/Artifacts; Landscapes; English Writing; Galilee
  - A view of the ruins of a synagogue at Tell Hum., 1866; ref426; Phillips, Henry, Sergeant, Active 1865-1867; 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital Copy Only - 030_ref422-ref425)
    Albumen Prints; Photographic Prints; Archaeological Sites/Artifacts; Landscapes; English Writing; Synagogues; Religious Sites; Buildings; Men; Regional/National Dress; Galilee; Palestine
  - A view of the Sea of Galilee in Northern Palestine., 1866; ref427; Phillips, Henry, Sergeant, Active 1865-1867; 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital Copy Only - 030_ref422-ref425)
    Albumen Prints; Photographic Prints; Sea of Galilee/Lake Tiberias; Lakes; Landscapes; Palestine; Water
  - An aqueduct at Khan Minyeh, Plain of Ghuweir., 1866; ref428; Phillips, Henry, Sergeant, Active 1865-1867; 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital Copy Only - 030_ref422-ref425)
    Albumen Prints; Photographic Prints; Men; Regional/National Dress; Landscapes; Palestine; English Writing; Archaeological Sites/Artifacts; Mountains/Hills
  - A view of Mount Arbel., 1866; ref429; Phillips, Henry, Sergeant, Active 1865-1867; 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital Copy Only - 030_ref422-ref425)
    Albumen Prints; Photographic Prints; Mountains/Hills; Landscapes; Palestine; English Writing; Galilee; Golan Heights
  - A view looking down Wadi Hamam., 1866; ref430; Phillips, Henry, Sergeant, Active 1865-1867; 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital Copy Only - 030_ref422-ref425)
    Albumen Prints; Photographic Prints; Landscapes; Mountains/Hills; English Writing; Palestine; Wadi Hamam, Galilee
  - A panoramic view of Jezreel., 1866; ref431; Phillips, Henry, Sergeant, Active 1865-1867; 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital Copy Only - 030_ref422-ref425)
    Albumen Prints; Photographic Prints; English Writing; Landscapes; Buildings; Palestine; Marj Ibn Āmir/Jezreel valley; Jebel Faqqua/Mount Gilboa
  - A panoramic view of Jezreel., 1866; ref432; Phillips, Henry, Sergeant, Active 1865-1867; 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital Copy Only - 030_ref422-ref425)
    Albumen Prints; Photographic Prints; Landscapes; Mountains/Hills; Palestine; English Writing; Marj Ibn Āmir/Jezreel valley
  - A panoramic view of Mound of Beisan (Tell Beit She'an)., 1866; ref433; Phillips, Henry, Sergeant, Active 1865-1867; 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital Copy Only - 030_ref422-ref425)
    Albumen Prints; Photographic Prints; Landscapes; Palestine; English Writing; Mountains/Hills; Baysan/Baisan/Bisan
  - A street of columns in Samaria (Sebastia, Nablus)., 1866; ref434; Phillips, Henry, Sergeant, Active 1865-1867; 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital Copy Only - 030_ref422-ref425)
    Albumen Prints; Photographic Prints; Samaria/as-Sāmirah; Nablus; Palestine; Archaeological Sites/Artifacts; Buildings; English Writing; Architecture
  - An aerial view of Mount Ebal., 1866; ref435; Phillips, Henry, Sergeant, Active 1865-1867; 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital Copy Only - 030_ref422-ref425)
    Albumen Prints; Photographic Prints; English Writing; Nablus; Landscapes; Mountains/Hills; Jabal 'Aybāl/Mount Ebal, West Bank; Palestine
  - A view of a bedouin camp east of Nablus., 1866; ref436; Phillips, Henry, Sergeant, Active 1865-1867; 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital Copy Only - 030_ref422-ref425)
    Albumen Prints; Photographic Prints; Bedouins; Landscapes; Nablus; West Bank; English Writing; Mountains/Hills; Palestine
  - A rock hewn tomb in Shuafat., 1866; ref437; Phillips, Henry, Sergeant, Active 1865-1867; 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital Copy Only - 030_ref422-ref425)
    Albumen Prints; Photographic Prints; English Writing; Archaeological Sites/Artifacts; Tombs/Mausoleums; Buildings; Palestine; Shuafat, East Jerusalem; Religious Sites
  - Threshing-floor on Damascus Road (between Tell el-Fūl and Mount Scopus)., 1867; ref438; Phillips, Henry, Sergeant, Active 1865-1867; 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital Copy Only - 030_ref422-ref425)
    Albumen Prints; Photographic Prints; English Writing; Landscapes; Jerusalem; Palestine
  - A view of the Jericho Plain (between Wady Qelt and Tell es-Sultan)., 1867; ref439; Phillips, Henry, Sergeant, Active 1865-1867; 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital Copy Only - 030_ref422-ref425)
    Albumen Prints; Photographic Prints; Jericho; West Bank; Palestine; Landscapes; Mountains/Hills; English Writing; Wadi Qelt/Wadi Kelt
  - Tree (Ziziphus jujuba) in wadi at Ain Jidi (Ein Gedi)., 1867; ref440; Phillips, Henry, Sergeant, Active 1865-1867; 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital Copy Only - 030_ref422-ref425)
    Albumen Prints; Photographic Prints; English Writing; Landscapes; Mountains/Hills; Animals; Palestine; Ain Jidi/Ein Gedi; Oases
  - A group of people and animals gathered at the ford across the Jordan River (wady Nawaimeh)., 1867; ref441; Phillips, Henry, Sergeant, Active 1865-1867; 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital Copy Only - 030_ref422-ref425)
    Albumen Prints; Photographic Prints; English Writing; Jordan River; Rivers; Men; Children; Animals; Swimming; Palestine; Women; Water; Oases; Regional/National Dress; Horses; Group Portraits
  - A general view of Mount Nebo from the spring of Ain Neba, Jordan., 1867; ref442; Phillips, Henry, Sergeant, Active 1865-1867; 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital Copy Only - 030_ref422-ref425)
    Albumen Prints; Photographic Prints; English Writing; Landscapes; Mountains/Hills; Jabal Nībū/Mount Nebo, Jordan
  - Ruins of buildings with Ionic columns at Khurbet Es Suk, Jordan., 1867; ref443; Phillips, Henry, Sergeant, Active 1865-1867; 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital Copy Only - 030_ref422-ref425)
    Albumen Prints; Photographic Prints; Archaeological Sites/Artifacts; Jordan; English Writing
  - A view of Wadi Qelt., Circa 1865-1867; ref444; Phillips, Henry, Sergeant, Active 1865-1867; 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital Copy Only - 030_ref422-ref425)
    Albumen Prints; Photographic Prints; Landscapes; Mountains/Hills; Wadi Qelt/Wadi Kelt; English Writing; Palestine
  - Original Photograph descriptions from Hisham Khatib's library, no date; ref445; 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital Copy Only - 030_ref422-ref425)
- Egypt - Zangaki, Arnoux and Sebah, ref728 (Object Digital copy only - 030_ref446-483)
  - No 208 - Grotte de l'Esbequie, Caire, Caire (Two men sitting in front of the grotto in Ezbekieh Gardens, Cairo)., Circa 1867-90; ref446; Zangaki Brothers; 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital copy only - 030_ref446-483)
    Albumen Prints; Photographic Prints; French Writing; Caves; Men; Group Portraits; Outdoors; Buildings; Gardens; Al Azbakeyah (Cairo, Egypt); Parks; Fez/Tarboush; Facial Hair; Hats
  - Ecluse amont a Ismailia (A Lock at Ismailia)., Circa 1860-90; ref447; Zangaki Brothers; 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital copy only - 030_ref446-483)
    Albumen Prints; Photographic Prints; Ismailia, Egypt; Bridges; Boats/Ships; Transportation; Rivers
  - No 236 - Vue du Caire et Mosquée de Mohamed Aly (A view of Cairo and the Mosque of Muhammed Ali)., Circa 1860-90; ref448; Zangaki Brothers; 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital copy only - 030_ref446-483)
    Albumen Prints; Photographic Prints; Mosques; Religious Sites; Buildings; Architecture; Cairo, Egypt; French Writing
  - No 902 - Denderah Colonnade., Circa 1860-90; ref449; Zangaki Brothers; 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital copy only - 030_ref446-483)
    Albumen Prints; Photographic Prints; Egyptian Hieroglyphics; Archaeological Sites/Artifacts; Architecture; Buildings; French Writing; Dendera, Egypt
  - No 720 - Bazar des Mandarins (A group of people at the Bazaar of Mandarins, Egypt)., Circa 1860-90; ref450; Zangaki Brothers; 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital copy only - 030_ref446-483)
    Albumen Prints; Photographic Prints; Men; Women; Children; Girls; Boys; Group Portraits; Buildings; Architecture; French Writing; Regional/National Dress; Egypt; Outdoors; Men; Food; Head Covers/Veils
  - Plan du Canal Maritime de Suez (A map of the Suez Canal)., Circa 1870-90; ref451; Zangaki Brothers; 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital copy only - 030_ref446-483)
    Albumen Prints; Photographic Prints; Individual Portraits; Maps; Suez, Egypt; English Writing; French Writing; Pasha
  - No 297 - Vue du Caire et mosquée Sultan Hassan (A view of Cairo and the Mosque of Sultan Hassan)., Circa 1860-90; ref452; Zangaki Brothers; 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital copy only - 030_ref446-483)
    Photographic Prints; Albumen Prints; Mosques; Religious Sites; Buildings; Architecture; Cairo, Egypt; French Writing; Mosque-Madrassa of Sultan Hassan
  - No 252 - Intérieur de la Mosquée de Mohamed (Interior of the Mosque of Muhammed Ali, Cairo)., Circa 1860-90; ref453; Zangaki Brothers; 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital copy only - 030_ref446-483)
    Albumen Prints; Photographic Prints; Mosques; Religious Sites; Architecture; Buildings; Cairo, Egypt; French Writing; English Writing; Mosque of Muhammad Ali Pasha
  - No 15 - Quai du Port Said (Quay at Port Said)., Circa 1860-90; ref454; Zangaki Brothers; 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital copy only - 030_ref446-483)
    Photographic Prints; Albumen Prints; Boats/Ships; Transportation; Port Said, Egypt; French Writing; English Writing; Seas; Mediterranean Sea; Crowds; Buildings; Ports; Landscapes
  - 655bis - Brindisi - Colonna Erculea (Column of the Harbour in Brindisi, Italy)., unknown date; ref455; Unknown; 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital copy only - 030_ref446-483)
    Photographic Prints; Albumen Prints; English Writing; Buildings; Architecture; Monuments/Memorials; Brindisi, Italy; Archaeological Sites/Artifacts
  - 649 - Galerie avec bassin du Palais de Choubra (A view of the pool of the Shubra Palace)., Circa 1850-80; ref456; Pascal Sebah, Constantinople (Beyoglu, Istanbul, Turkey); 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital copy only - 030_ref446-483)
    Photographic Prints; Choubra/Shubra, Egypt; Palaces; Buildings; Architecture; Water; Ponds; Men; French Writing
  - No 372 - Palais d'Abdin, Caire (The Abdeen Palace, Cairo)., Circa 1860-90; ref457; Zangaki Brothers; 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital copy only - 030_ref446-483)
    Photographic Prints; Albumen Prints; Buildings; Architecture; French Writing; Palaces; Abdin, Cairo, Egypt; Streets/Roads; Street Lamps; Mosques
  - No 396 - Sphink et pyramide (A group of people and camels with the Sphinx and the Pyramids of Giza)., Circa 1860-90; ref458; Zangaki Brothers; 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital copy only - 030_ref446-483)
    Photographic Prints; Albumen Prints; The Great Sphinx of Giza; Giza, Egypt; Pyramids; Statues/Sculptures; Architecture; Archaeological Sites/Artifacts; French Writing; Men; Regional/National Dress; Camels; Animals
  - No 284 - Cour de la Mosquée El-Azhar, réunion des théologies, Caire (Reunion of the theologies at the Court of the Al-Azhar Mosque, Cairo)., Circa 1860-90; ref459; Zangaki Brothers; 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital copy only - 030_ref446-483)
    Photographic Prints; Albumen Prints; Cairo, Egypt; Mosques; Religious Sites; Men; Regional/National Dress; Turbans; Architecture; Buildings; French Writing
  - 261 - A view of the Mosque of Muhammed Ali, Cairo., Circa 1860-90; ref460; Zangaki Brothers; 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital copy only - 030_ref446-483)